BEAU HODES

CONTACT

BEAUHODES@GMAIL.COM BEAUHODES.COM

PROFILE

Software developer specifically interested in blockchain/DeFi applications and scaling, trading/market research, and fintech products with the goal of finding creative business solutions for new technology. I am a very quick, motivated learner who thrives in a fast-paced environment and enjoys complex problem solving.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE MAY 2021

Solidity/EVM

Hardhat/Foundry

• JavaScript/Node.js

• Cloud: GCP/Azure

• Data Structures/Algorithms

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | LAWRENCE, KS GPA: 3.90 MAJOR, 3.83 OVERALL ACT: 33

SKILLS

- Python
- C++/C
- Git
- Excel/Office
- SQL
- HTML/CSS

PROJECTS

NFT LOTTERY

JANUARY 2022

 Solidity implementation and tests for an NFT lottery game where sellers can deposit NFTs and users can deposit tokens for a chance to win the NFT. Not used in production for legal reasons.

ALERT BOTS

2021-2022

 Use Python, JavaScript, and various APIs to send out alerts for trading volume spikes, Twitter follows, and trending searches.

PERSONAL SPEECH TRAINER

IN PROGRESS

• Uses a respiratory sensor and Python to help those who stutter, including myself, work on their fluency using computer visuals.

PROGMON

NOVEMBER 2019

 Along with 4 classmates, created a basic fighting game, called Progmon, using Python and Pygame. My responsibilities included game flow design, computer logic, test suite development, and graphic design.

EXPERIENCE

CO-FOUNDER & RESEARCHER

UPNOW CRYPTO RESEARCH | SEPTEMBER 2021-CURRENT

- UpNow Crypto Research is a firm dedicated to providing in-depth market research, insights, and education to anyone interested in cryptocurrencies and crypto markets
- Publish bi-weekly research, daily updates, and curated educational content/tutorials
- Developed website(s) and platform layouts

DEVELOPER

CBAL | MAY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

- CBAi is an AI and data services startup
- Completed multiple backend integrations on behalf of clients in Node.js
- Advised on a multi-chain NFT marketplace and an AI-based price prediction model
- Wrote the initial backend architecture for an NFT marketplace

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

PORT TMS | MAY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Port TMS is a cloud-based transportation management software company founded in 2018
- General programmer; implemented, from back end to front end, a web interface for company developers to save time in the creation and management customer data reports

KU LEADERSHIP CHALLENGE

JANUARY 2020

 Two day seminar promoting leadership skills and networking sponsored by corporate affiliates

OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- Backend Developer at Clear Contracts, 2021-2022
- Operations Intern at Lockton Companies, 2020
- Data Analytics Consultant at Astra Innovations, 2019-2020
- Web Designer at Midland Metal, 2017

CERTIFICATES

CRYPTOCURRENCY AND BLOCKCHAIN

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA (ONLINE) | JANUARY 2021

SEQUENCES, TIME SERIES, AND PREDICITON IN TENSORFLOW DEEPLEARNING.AI | AUGUST 2020

BLOOMBERG MARKET CONCEPTS

BLOOMBERG LP | APRIL 2020

IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

COURSERA/IBM | SEPTEMBER 2019

 Nine-course certificate using Python and various algorithms

MICROSOFT: AZURE207X —"DATABASES IN AZURE" EDX | MARCH 2019

SELECTED COURSEWORK

- Software Engineering: Systematic development of software products including life-cycle models, teams, tools, testing, planning, and estimating. Also covered Agile development and Git version-control.
- Others: Computer Algorithms, Data Structures, Compiler Construction, Machine Learning, Computer Security, Calculus I-III, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Databases, Computer Forensics